

Rudraksh Kawadkar

E-commerce Data Analyst | Retail Customer Service CRM | Amazon Development Center India

+91 - 9755912216 | kawadkarrudraksh9@gmail.com

Profile Summary

Analytics professional currently working as E-commerce Data Analyst at Amazon Development Center India PVT LTD with over 5+ years of overall experience and a year of strong experience in Data Analysis, Modelling, Mining, Validation & Visualization with large data sets of Structured and Unstructured Data. A year of working experience with big data tools & technologies.

I am a great **Data Science enthusiast** and having been certified in **Master in Data Science With Power BI**, I've done many projects like **Amazon Seller Sales Analysis** where I gained hands-on experience with tools like **Python** and its libraries **Pandas**, **NumPy**, **Matplotlib**, and **Seaborn** to perform **Data research**, **Data visualization**, **and Market Research**.

I've also worked with **Database Management Tools like SQL Server Management Studio** and am well-versed with **DDL**, **DML Statements, Joins, and Functions**.

Work Experience

E-commerce Data Analyst (Retail)

Dec 2018 - Present

Amazon Development Center India PVT LTD

- Extensive experience in **Data Analytics** for satisfying marketing campaigns.
- Good knowledge of Spark Architecture and its ecosystem.
- Having extensive knowledge of the PySpark Framework in storage, writing queries, processing, and data analysis.
- Imported information from different sources such as AWS S3, and EC2 and converted them into Spark Dataframe for analyzing data.
- Worked on various file formats like Parquet, CSV, JSON, etc.
- Experience in optimizing the Spark Jobs and Hive SQL Queries.
- Improved query performance by applying various spark optimization techniques.
- Good knowledge of business process analysis, performance measurement, and quality.
- Cleaning, Pre-import Validation & Data Analysis through Pandas to predict and forecast the outcome for the business, and complete market research by applying the data aggregation and graphical representation using Matplotlib and Seaborn.
- Using customer and seller data, market trends, and reports to get a clear picture of the department's operations and ways to improve them.
- Numerical Analysis using the NumPy for the given dataset.
- Quick learner and up-to-date with industry trends, excellent written and oral communication. Analytical and problem-solving skills, good team player, ability to work independently, and well organized.
- Awarded the "Best Employee of the Year" above and beyond performance during the Financial Year 2020.

Software Developer (Android)

Sept 2016 - Feb 2018

Emorphis Technologies PVT LTD

- Design and build applications for the Android platform.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.
- Help maintain code quality, organization, and automatization.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages - Python, SQL

Big Data Technologies - PySpark, Yarn, Databricks, Azure Data

Factory

Data Processing & Visualization - Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib,

Seaborn, Plotly

BI Reporting - Power BI

Database & Web Services - SQL. Amazon Web Services

Application Servers and Frameworks - Jupyter Notebook, SQL

Server Management Studio

Operating System - Windows 10

Soft Skills & Abilities

- Effective communication and negotiation skills.
- Exploratory Data Analysis.
- Project Management & Process Optimization.

Education & Certification

Master of Computer Applications Devi Ahilya University	2013 - 2016
Bachelor of Computer Applications Devi Ahilya University	2010 - 201
High School Examination Madhya Pradesh Board of Education	2007 - 2009
Secondary School Examination Madhya Pradesh Board of Education	1995 - 2007
Masters in Data Science with PowerBl	

Rewards & Recognition

- Individual Excellence Award For consistent performance as a Software Developer.
- The employee of the Year Award Excellent performance during the financial year 2020.

Get in touch!

Console Flare

Mobile: +91-9755912216

Email: kawadkarrudrakshg@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/rudraksh-kawadkar

Projects

Amazon Seller Sales Analysis FY 2021-22

- · Identification of the sales over dates.
- · Finding most sales based on states.
- Payment method analysis for the products sold and identification of the products returned to the seller.
- · What was the shipping fee based on the payment method
- Correlation Analysis.

North America Retail Warehouse and Customer Satisfaction Analysis

- Analyzing and visualizing the number of warehouses in geography.
- · Analyzing order price and order total.
- Analyzing and visualizing how many customers are happy with the service.

Amazon Seller Sales Analysis FY 2021-22

- Most of our sales come from Budget older families, mainstream young singles/couples and mainstream retires.
- The higher sales in the case of the mainstream category are due to higher customers in retired and young single/couples. But the same is not in the case of the budget category, as older singles/couples have the highest customer proportion in budget but the sales are higher in the case of budget Older families.
- Older families and Young families buy more chips per customer.
- The largest size is 380g and the smallest size is 70g.
- The no. of transactions(sales) kept on increasing till 24th
 December 2018 and then there is a break in the graph on
 25th Dec 2018. The break is due to the day being a
 Christmas day on which shops and all remain closed and
 therefore there were no transactions(sales) on that
 particular day.

Big Data Analytics of Amazon USA Customer Reviews

- Identifying the total number of products present in the dataset.
- Calculating average product rating reviews for each product.
- Figuring out N-reviewed products sorted by count.
- Overall product rating for all those products which are present in the top N-reviewed products.
- Identification of all the users who have reviewed each product.
- Finding all the records partitioned by the date on which the product was reviewed.
- Finding all the product information for each unique star rating of the product by dividing it into different categories/bins.
- Recommending the products to the user based on the star rating.
- Finding the count of the reviews grouped by date for each product.
- Finding the count of products for each product star rating.